Tanim Mahmud

Full Stack Web Developer

Unit 4 85 Droop Street Footscray, vic - 3011 **0430808098**

tanimmahmud08@gmail.com tanimmahmud.github.io

SUMMARY

I studied to become a Civil Engineer but fall in love with coding while I was doing my 4th-year university research using MATLAB. It took me to my school days when I used to spend nights solving math challenges. I was missing those thrill nights. I really enjoy the joy of solving difficult problems.

I am a young talented and energetic web developer. I have displayed my pair coding skills in free code camps front end development course. I have developed efficient teamwork capabilities; working with culturally diverse teams. I have the initiative drive to succeed and I always take the innovative approach. Through my diploma degree in Software development, I have developed effective problem-solving skills and thus I am prepared to take on significant responsibility early in my professional career.

EXPERIENCE

Geo Steel BD Limited — Structural Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2014 - 2016

Responsibilities:

- Prepared structural drawing and detail drawings using AutoCAD software for residential and commercial buildings.
- Organized and evaluated all shop drawings for structural programs.
- Performed design calculations manually and using SPACE GASS softwares. Report to the building concierge if there are any issues.
- Assisted in carrying research on project design requirements.

Student — Coder Factory Academy

Melbourne, Australia

2016 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Detecting and Debugging Errors In Applications.
- Developing web application using HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, and Javascript.
- Executing Computer science fundamentals into applications.
- Designing Database and Application Architecture.
- Integrating third party applications (APIs).
- Utilise cloud-based deployment systems.

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

jQuery

Bootstrap

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

AutoCAD

AWARDS

1st runner-up- Bangladesh Mathematical Olympiad

Merit Award- The Government of Bangladesh

LANGUAGES

English

Bangla

• Implementing application fundamentals into Mobile technology .

Student — Rmit University

Melbourne, Australia

2010 - 2013

Responsibilities:

- Involved in the planning, design, construction, supervision, management and maintenance of the infrastructure projects necessary for the functioning of our modern community.
- Developing a sustainability framework for engineering decision-making, Developing personal and professional capabilities in sustainability, problem-solving and decision-making, technical competence, communication, and teamwork.

EDUCATION

Coder Factory Academy, Australia — Diploma of Software Development

2016 - 2017

Rmit University, Melbourne, Australia — Bachelor of Engineering (Civil and Infrastructure) (Honours)

2010 - 2013

Major: Structural Engineering.

Thesis: Probabilistic solution to assessment of corrosion in steel

reinforcement in concrete.

PROJECTS

JrDevJobs

November 2016

Descriptions:

A website for both Coder Factory students and interested employers, to showcase their skills and find talented Junior developers, respectively.

Problem

As Coder Factory students have to have a month internship in order to graduate from the course and employers

used to visit different websites to look for the potential candidates among coder factory students. It would be time saving and convenient for employers to only visit one website where all the relevant information from candidates will be listed and they can find the right candidates for their company.

Solution

A service that will allow Coder Factory students to create a profile and list all of their qualifications, experiences, skills, contact details with a headshot and little about them. Their profile will have a summary of their GitHub account so it will be easy for employers to drive into students recent or past projects if they are interested. Companies will also be able to create an account and post jobs if they think they want Coder Factory graduates to apply for any particular jobs or they can message students if they think they will be a better match for the position.

Personal Portfolio website

October 2016

Descriptions:

My aim was to develop a clean accessible website for prospective employers and fellow developers. I used bigger font size and black and white color combinations for accessible reasons. I tried to create a simple website with no fancy animation or parallax because it suits me better. I decided to go with different Html and CSS file for each page because it is easy to debug and as I used Jekyll, it helped me to organize my files and folders.

Coder Bank Banking App

August 2016

Descriptions:

The aim of this project was to build a terminal app using ruby where a customer can

- create a new account,
- login to his account to update details,
- transfer money to another account,
- receive money from another account,
- edit password and email address,
- access to his statement,
- see his current balance,
- search saved contacts and transfer money to their account.

Probabilistic solution to assessment of corrosion in steel reinforcement in concrete. (Thesis Project)

January 2013 - November 2013

Descriptions:

The investigation concerned the service probabilistic solution to assessment of corrosion in steel reinforcement in concrete, in terms of chloride-induced steel corrosion. To calculate the time to steel corrosion, the rate of chloride transport in the identical concrete mix to the structure and the chloride threshold level for corrosion

was assumed by a literature review published data. Then, the Monte Carlo Simulation was used to calculate the probability of steel corrosion in reinforced concrete. In the investigation, we have discussed the key parameters such as concrete cover, Chloride threshold level, Chloride diffusion coefficient, Surface chloride concentration, the exposure conditions, and mix design etc to identify the time to onset of corrosion in steel reinforcement in concrete.

Key outcomes and skills developed:

- Carried out an extensive literature review on a research topic and develop an understanding of how other Engineers have addressed similar issues.
- Modelled probabilistic method using Matlab, Spss, EasyFit and wrote scientific findings using LaTeX and Endnote.
- Collated necessary data for the project and developed a research methodology and a plan to arrive at a solution to the specific problems.
- Prepared an engineering report to a professional standard.

High Rise building Structures

July 2013 - November 2013

Descriptions:

The project was to deliver the conceptual design of a high-rise structure which consisted of dual occupancy – work/office and living/residential space with adequate retail and recreation facilities. A collaborative design consortium was a mix of architectural team, Gravity load resisting team and lateral load resisting team. I was a part of the Gravity load resisting team.

Key outcomes and skills developed:

- Carried out preliminary estimation in detail, including the dimensioning of the primary, secondary and composite beams used throughout the structure, as well as the design and implementation of the axial load resisting structures through the use of composite columns and conventional steel columns.
- Modelled and analysed the whole structure using the SPACEGASS software package to determine the member forces generated within the structure.
- Evaluated and compared key performance indicator.
- Designed in compliance with the following Australian Standards;
 - o AS1170.3 (Design Actions)
 - AS2327.1 (Composite Structures)
 - AS5100.6 (Composite Columns)
 - o AS4100 (Steel Design)
- Design has also been used in conjunction with the data provided in the "Bondek Design and Construction Manual" as published by the manufacturer Lysaght®, a subsidiary of BlueScope Steel.

Sustainable design House

July 2012 - November 2012

Descriptions:

Dream house project was designed to broaden our design knowledge and also to introduce us to "think green" at an early stage of our career. we were introduced to structural timber design and this project introduced the concepts of civil infrastructure design with a sustainability focus. In this project we learnt to deal with different stages of life cycle, namely, planning, implementation (engineering & construction), and operation (in-service) phases.

Key outcomes and skills developed:

- Designed a two storey house using timber structures and a reinforcement concrete slab.
- Researched and adopted a best practice in order to maximise sustainable features in the house.
- Prepared structural drawing using AutoCAD software and REVIT software.